So, if I asked you what a promise is,
you would probably say it's an agreement
between two parties. So, for example, if
I promised to give you ice cream at some
point in the future, as long as I
eventually gave you that ice cream, you
would say that I'd fulfilled my promise.
In fact, you'd probably resolve me of my
obligation to give you more ice cream
because I promised to give you ice cream
and then I gave you ice cream. Once you
receive the ice cream, you're probably
going to eat the ice cream. Um, you'll
probably take some action as a result of
receiving the thing I promised.
Well, now let's take that same scenario.
Um, let's say I promised you ice cream
and then a couple hours later I came
back and handed you broccoli. Well, you
probably reject that because that is not
the thing I promised you. I promised you
ice cream and I brought you broccoli and
so my instead of resolving my
obligation, I will have given you
something that you rejected. Well,
promises work like this in JavaScript.
In JavaScript, a promise is just a
special kind of variable. And what it
does is it either resolves if the code
runs correctly or it rejects it if the
code doesn't run correctly. And so you
can write your code that says, "Hey,
wait until we get back the results that
we were expecting." And promises make
our life a lot easier.